techuntold.com 2019-11-01

# Privacy Policy And Disclaimer

TechUntold.com privacy policy and the disclaimer was **Last Updated** and posted on May 24, 2018. It governs the privacy and governing terms of our website, located at [techuntold.com](https://www.techuntold.com/).

At www.techuntold.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by www.techuntold.com and how it is used.

## Who We Are

**Company Name** – TechUntold Media Enterprise.

**Contact Information** – admin@techuntold.com

**Address**

58, Teg Bahadur Road – 3rd,

Dehradun.

Site URL – https://www.techuntold.com/

### What Information Do We Collect & Why Do We Collect This Data?

We collect your personal information when you subscribe to any of our newsletters or contact us using the contact form.

You may have to enter name and Email address when subscribing to our newsletters, contacting us or leaving a comment.

**Email Subscription**

Your name and email is collected after your **consent** (by checking the checkbox) for the purpose of sending you updates from our site directly to your email address.

You can always unsubscribe anytime using the Unsubscribe option which is available in every email we send.

**Contact Forms**

We receive your name and Email address after your **consent**  (by checking the checkbox) when you contact us using our contact form. We keep this data for customer service purposes, but you do not use the information submitted to them for marketing purposes.

**Comments**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form after your **consent** , and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

Name and email address are used for contacting our users or sending them latest updates on our blog.

**Cookies**

TechUntold.com does collect cookies automatically when you visit our site on your browser. Please note that cookie is a non-personal information that is not personally identifiable to you and allows TechUntold.com to recognize you each time you visit or login to our site. TechUntold.com doesn’t use cookies to store visitor’s information. 

Third party services such as Google Adsense, Readwhere and Google Analytics which we use on our site store cookies to track visitors and for better ad management. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on www.techuntold.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

TechUntold.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

For any concern with a third party, please contact them directly.

**External Links**

TechUnold has links to other websites on its pages that are not under our direct control. Once you have left TechUntold.com and landed on another site, then it’s their privacy policy that comes into action. We won’t be able to control a user’s privacy on another site. We cannot also be held liable/accountable for any loss/damage occurring as a result of activity on another website.

**Affiliates**

TechUntold.com uses Amazon associates program for promoting products from Amazon through affiliate links. Whenever a user buys a product from those links, we earn a commission. However, we only recommend relevant products that have high ratings and positive reviews. Apart from that, we are also affiliate partners with other quality products like mSpy and Stellar Data Recovery.

**Embedded Content From Other Websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

**Analytics**

We use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our website.

  * **Google Analytics** Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity. 

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>

## Who We Share Your Data With

The following is a list of third party services that may access your data at various times:

  * MailChimp for Email marketing
  * Convert Pro for capturing your Emails.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers, sites, services for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. www.techuntold.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or websites.

### How Long We Retain Your Data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

### What Rights You Have Over Your Data

**Where We Send Your Data?**

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

**Do We Disclose Any information To Outside Parties?**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information.

**How Can I Delete My Data?**

Please [contact us](https://www.techuntold.com/contact-us/) to request your account, and it’s associated data, to be deleted from TechUntold.com, and associated servers.

**How Can I Export My Data?**

Please [contact us](https://www.techuntold.com/contact-us/) to request your account, and it’s associated data, to be exported from TechUntold.

### How We Protect Your Data

We use SSL certificate and password and API keys that are regularly cycled for security purposes .

In addition to this, the following precautions have been made:

  * Database access is strictly limited to those requiring it
  * Server access is strictly limited to those requiring it
  * Administrator roles are designed such that those performing routine administrative tasks do not gain access to data that is not relevant to their role

### What Data Breach Procedures We Have In Place

In the unlikely case of a data breach, the following steps will be followed:

  * Site, server and database access will temporarily be disabled
  * All of our passwords and security certificates will be changed
  * Our users will be emailed and notified of the breach
  * An internal investigation will be started to ascertain as much as we can about the breach
  * The TechUntold.com site, server and databases will be re-enabled once they’ve been proven to be secure
  * Changes will be made, and documented, to prevent a similar breach in the future
  * A follow up an email will be sent to all of our users, detailing what we learned from the investigation, along with the steps to prevent future breaches

### Privacy Policy Updates

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time. You should review this Privacy Policy frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we may notify you on our Website, by a blog post, by email, or by any method we determine. The method we chose is at our sole discretion. We will also change the “Last Updated” date at the beginning of this Privacy Policy. Any changes we make to our privacy policy are effective as of this Last Updated date and replace any prior Privacy Policies.

### Question About Our Privacy Policy

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at admin@techuntold.com.
